Department of Drama and Dance Records UA070
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Drama and Dance Records
1943-1985
1878-2009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Arts and Sciences
Department of Drama and Dance
UA070
45.4 Linear Feet 69 boxes
1 Volumes
1 Artifact(s)
47 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into three series: Drama department productions; Photographic slides of productions; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Department of Drama and Dance formally came into existence on September 1, 1983. The Department of Drama absorbed the Dance Program which had been part of the Department of Physical Education to create the newly formed department. Professor Sherwood Collins, who had been the Chair of the Department of Drama remained as the head of the newly expanded department. Associate Professor Alice Trexler who had been at the helm of the Dance Program remained as its director after the formation of the new department had been officially completed.
The Department of Drama and Dance articulated information about the Department in the Bulletin of Tuft University for the academic year 1984-1985 as follows, "Through the study of drama and theater arts, the student can cultivate an understanding and appreciation of one of Western society's main civilizing forces; develop powers of intellect, imagination, emotion, and vocal and bodily expressiveness, as well as standards of good taste and workmanship; and gain a sound foundation for later pursuit of interests in this field". Regarding the Dance Program, the Bulletin stated, "The objectives of the Tufts dance program are to acquaint the student with both dance technique and dance theory within the realm of a liberal arts education".
The Department of Drama and Dance offers graduate programs leading to a Master of Arts as well as a Doctor of Philosophy.
Dance is a component of the Department of Drama and Dance, operating within the liberal arts philosophy with beginning to advanced courses. Events vary by semester, including informal presentations of faculty/student/guest work. Creativity and critical thinking are stressed in classes. The program serves the liberal arts goals rather than having a conservatory orientation even though several or more of our courses offer opportunities for students to continue with advanced skills. Modern dance is the core curricular element along with several non-western forms offered during the year.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Scope and Contents
This collection comprises materials pertaining to dramatic productions presented by the Department of Drama and Speech, Graduate Dramatic Society, Arena Theater, Tufts Summer Theater, Tufts Community Players, Magic Circle, Cup and Saucer, and Pen, Paint and Pretzels. It also contains administrative files for the Department of Drama and Dance. Materials consist mostly of production photographs, slides, prompt books, rehearsal schedules, stage diagrams, and programs. For further Pen, Paint and Pretzels (3 P's) materials or for materials pertaining to productions presented jointly by the Drama Department and the 3 P's, consult the 3 P's collection.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Student Activities -- Performing Arts; Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work; Theater; Dance
- Drama Department Productions, 1878 -- 1993; UA070.001; 18.95 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes; 1 Artifact(s); 1 Digital Object(s)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains photos and records of groups and productions associated with Drama department.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by group responsible for the production.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Records containing information related to student education, staff and faculty employment, and Board of Trustees records are closed for 75 years from the date of creation.
  - Theater photographs, 1966 -- 1973; UA070.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    Open for research.
  - Theater photographs, 1950 -- 1970; UA070.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Theater photographs, 1935; UA070.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Theater photographs, 1935 -- 1960; UA070.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Theater photographs, 1935 -- 1960; UA070.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Theater photographs, 1935 -- 1960; UA070.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Photograph of outdoor production of "Old Furtunatus", 1907; UA070.001.001.00007 (Box Shared 46)
    This photograph was found uncatalogued in the stacks in summer 2007. Note its different location; it is housed in a separate box with other oversize materials.
  - Photograph of outdoor production of "Old Furtunatus", 1907; UA070.001.001.00008 (Box Shared 46)
  - Photograph of Jackson production of "The Rose and the Ring", 1912; UA070.001.001.00009 (Box Shared 46)
  - Drama Dept. photos, 1961; UA070.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, general, 1931 -- 1967; UA070.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, curriculum and degrees, 1963 -- 1964; UA070.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Drama Arena Theater: general, 1945 -- 1961; UA070.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Drama Arena Theater: correspondence, 1950 -- 1966; UA070.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, drama and speech, correspondence, 1950 -- 1966; UA070.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, dramatic productions, 1951 -- 1961; UA070.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department examinations, 1960 -- 1980; UA070.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, theater board: minutes, 1949 -- 1960; UA070.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Drama Arena Theater: productions, 1900 -- 1958; UA070.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Drama Department, creative dramatics program, 1954 -- 1965; UA070.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, cup and saucer, 1964 -- 1972; UA070.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, curriculum, 1968; UA070.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Graduate Dramatic Society, 1930 -- 1948; UA070.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Jackson and Alumnae, 1910 -- 1925; UA070.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Dramatic Society, 1878 -- 1929; UA070.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Magic Circle Theater: photos, 1961 -- 1964; UA070.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Magic Circle: applications, 1961; UA070.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Magic Circle: applications, 1962 -- 1963; UA070.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Magic Circle: applications, 1964 -- 1965; UA070.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Drama Department, Magic Circle: miscellaneous, 1952 -- 1971; UA070.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Drama Department, PPP: general, 1917 -- 1933; UA070.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Pen, Paints, and Pretzels of Tufts College, minutes, 1940 -- 1950; UA070.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - PPP accounts, 1950 -- 1970; UA070.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Pen, Paint, and Pretzels account book, 1950 -- 1956; UA070.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - PPP accounts, 1946 -- 1953; UA070.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Pen, Paint, & Pretzels, accounting record, 1937 -- 1946; UA070.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Summer Theater: applications, 1965 -- 1978; UA070.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Summer Theater: production programs, 1947 -- 1974; UA070.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Drama Department, Tufts Summer Theater: publicity forms, 1962 -- 1963; UA070.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - List of productions, 1943 -- 1981; UA070.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Ralph Roister Doister, 1895; UA070.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Drama Department, Comus, 1901; UA070.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Drama Department, Old Fortunatus, 1906; UA070.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
    - The Queen's retinue in the Old Fortunatus production, 1906; UA070.001.006.00004.00001 (Box 6)
      Theater; Theater, Open-air; Drama; Students; Student activities; Plays; Whittemore, Thomas; Dekker, Thomas, ca. 1572-1632
  - Drama Department, A Point of Honor, 1910 -- 1911; UA070.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Dept. of Drama and Speech, Two for the Seesaw, 1964; UA070.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Dept. of Drama and Speech, Epitaph for George Dillon, 1965; UA070.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Cup and Saucer, overtones, 1952; UA070.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Monkey's Paw, 1953; UA070.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Tunnel of Love, 1954; UA070.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Aria Da Capo, 1957; UA070.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Deidre, 1959; UA070.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Arlecchino Innamorato, 1964; UA070.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Balloon, 1964; UA070.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Caesar and Cleopatra, 1964; UA070.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Escurial, 1964; UA070.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Goat Sings, 1964; UA070.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Measures Taken, 1965; UA070.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Abyss, 1972; UA070.001.008.00012 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Detour, 1972; UA070.001.008.00013 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Money Makes the World Go Round, 1972; UA070.001.008.00014 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Comings and Goings, 1977; UA070.001.008.00015 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Stone, 1978; UA070.001.008.00016 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Come Into the Garden Maud, 1979; UA070.001.008.00017 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Counting the Ways, 1979; UA070.001.008.00018 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Crossroads, 1979; UA070.001.008.00019 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Lover, 1979; UA070.001.008.00020 (Box 8)
  - Cup and Saucer, Passion, Poison and Petrifaction, 1979; UA070.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Rook, 1979; UA070.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Slam the Door Softly, 1979; UA070.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Charlie, 1980; UA070.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, The Intruder, 1980; UA070.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Le Guichet, 1980; UA070.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Sganarelle, 1980; UA070.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Hortense Said, 1981; UA070.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, announcements, 1981 -- 1982; UA070.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - Cup and Saucer, Picnic on the Battlefield, 1982; UA070.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Capitalist's Son, 1946; UA070.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Green Grow the Lilacs, 1947; UA070.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, I, A Stranger, 1948; UA070.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Listen My Children, 1949; UA070.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Kind Lady, 1950; UA070.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Lysistrata, 1950; UA070.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Curious Savage, 1951; UA070.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Dramatist, 1951; UA070.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Good Housekeeping, 1951; UA070.001.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Linden Tree, 1951; UA070.001.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Merchant of Yonkers, 1951; UA070.001.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, There's Always Juliet, 1951; UA070.001.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Courting of Marie Jenvrin, 1952; UA070.001.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Family Reunion, 1952; UA070.001.011.00001 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, House of Bernarda Alba, 1952; UA070.001.011.00002 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Voice of the Turtle, 1952; UA070.001.011.00003 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Arthur, 1953; UA070.001.011.00004 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Captive at Large, 1953; UA070.001.011.00005 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Happy as Larry, 1953; UA070.001.011.00006 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Miser, 1953; UA070.001.011.00007 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Passing Fancy, 1953; UA070.001.011.00008 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Thieves Carnival, 1953; UA070.001.011.00009 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Time of Storm, 1953; UA070.001.011.00010 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Concerto for One Small Voice, 1954; UA070.001.011.00011 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Fish are Dying in the Sea, 1954; UA070.001.011.00012 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Getting Married, 1954; UA070.001.011.00013 (Box 11)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Goodbye My Fancy, 1954; UA070.001.012.00001 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Infernal Machine, 1954; UA070.001.012.00002 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Ring 'Round the Moon, 1954; UA070.001.012.00003 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, When We Are Married, 1954; UA070.001.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Noah, 1955; UA070.001.012.00005 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Treasures of Pelican, 1955; UA070.001.012.00006 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Great Gesture, 1956; UA070.001.012.00007 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Love's Comedy, 1956; UA070.001.012.00008 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Amphitryon 38, 1957; UA070.001.012.00009 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Doctor Knock, 1957; UA070.001.012.00010 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Trojan Horse, 1957; UA070.001.012.00011 (Box 12)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, A Clearing in the Woods, 1958; UA070.001.013.00001 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Green Grows the Lilac, 1958; UA070.001.013.00002 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Mousetrap, 1958; UA070.001.013.00003 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Reluctant Debutante, 1958; UA070.001.013.00004 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Tartuffe, 1958; UA070.001.013.00005 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Torch Bearers, 1958; UA070.001.013.00006 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Alison's House, 1959; UA070.001.013.00007 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Burnt Flower Bed, 1959; UA070.001.013.00008 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Chalk Garden, 1959; UA070.001.013.00009 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Big Doorstep, 1959; UA070.001.013.00010 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Jack, or the Submission and the Lesson, 1959; UA070.001.013.00011 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Royal Family, 1959; UA070.001.013.00012 (Box 13)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Camille, 1961; UA070.001.014.00001 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Deadly Game, 1961; UA070.001.014.00002 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Prodigal, 1961; UA070.001.014.00003 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Right You Are (If You Think You Are), 1961; UA070.001.014.00004 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, All the Way Home, 1962; UA070.001.014.00005 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Back to Methuselah, 1962; UA070.001.014.00006 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, Romanticks, 1962; UA070.001.014.00007 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, A Touch of the Poet, 1962; UA070.001.014.00008 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Busy Martyr, 1963; UA070.001.014.00009 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Country Wife, 1963; UA070.001.014.00010 (Box 14)
  - Drama--Summer Theater, The Other Heart, 1963; UA070.001.014.00011 (Box 14)
  - Taste of Honey, 1964; UA070.001.015.00001 (Box 15)
  - Thomas With Two Souls, 1964; UA070.001.015.00002 (Box 15)
  - Under Milk Wood, 1964; UA070.001.015.00003 (Box 15)
  - The Way of the World, 1964; UA070.001.015.00004 (Box 15)
  - A Moon for the Misbegotten, 1965; UA070.001.015.00005 (Box 15)
  - The Physicists, 1965; UA070.001.015.00006 (Box 15)
  - The Rehearsal, 1965; UA070.001.015.00007 (Box 15)
  - When the Wind Blew Cool a Rosie's, 1965; UA070.001.015.00008 (Box 15)
  - And People All Around, 1966; UA070.001.015.00009 (Box 15)
  - Drama Dept., Othello, 1961; UA070.001.016.00001 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., The Silent Woman, 1961; UA070.001.016.00002 (Box 16)
  - Drama Dept., The Chinese Wall, 1962; UA070.001.016.00003 (Box 16)
  - The Beaux Strategem, 1966; UA070.001.017.00001 (Box 17)
  - La Ronde, 1966; UA070.001.017.00002 (Box 17)
  - Fairy Tales of New York, 1970; UA070.001.017.00003 (Box 17)
  - Lady Windermere's Fan, 1971; UA070.001.017.00004 (Box 17)
  - A Delicate Balance, 1972; UA070.001.017.00005 (Box 17)
  - Fall and Redemption of Man, 1972; UA070.001.017.00006 (Box 17)
  - Love for Love, 1972; UA070.001.018.00001 (Box 18)
  - Tango, 1972; UA070.001.018.00002 (Box 18)
  - Ryan's Yorktown Tune, 1975; UA070.001.018.00003 (Box 18)
  - A Fable, 1978; UA070.001.018.00004 (Box 18)
  - "R", 1978; UA070.001.018.00005 (Box 18)
  - She Stoops to Conquer, 1978; UA070.001.018.00006 (Box 18)
  - Tobacco Road, 1978; UA070.001.019.00001 (Box 19)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1979; UA070.001.019.00002 (Box 19)
  - The Man Who Came to Dinner, 1979; UA070.001.019.00003 (Box 19)
  - Open Season, 1979; UA070.001.019.00004 (Box 19)
  - The School for Scandal, 1979; UA070.001.019.00005 (Box 19)
  - Hay Fever, 1980; UA070.001.019.00006 (Box 19)
  - Holiday, 1980; UA070.001.019.00007 (Box 19)
  - The Lion in Winter, 1980; UA070.001.020.00001 (Box 20)
  - Loot, 1981; UA070.001.020.00002 (Box 20)
  - Thieves Carnival, 1981; UA070.001.020.00003 (Box 20)
  - Toys in the Attic, 1981; UA070.001.020.00004 (Box 20)
  - Drama--Summer Theater Productions, 1985; UA070.001.020.00005 (Box 20)
  - Gaslight, 1948; UA070.001.021.00001 (Box 21)
  - The Circle, 1949; UA070.001.021.00002 (Box 21)
  - Peck's Bad Boy, 1940; UA070.001.021.00003 (Box 21)
  - The Makropoulos Secret, 1950; UA070.001.021.00004 (Box 21)
  - Night Must Fall, 1950; UA070.001.021.00005 (Box 21)
  - Nothing But the Truth, 1950; UA070.001.021.00006 (Box 21)
  - Arsenic and Old Lace, 1951; UA070.001.021.00007 (Box 21)
  - Mr. Barry's Etchings, 1951; UA070.001.021.00008 (Box 21)
  - The Vinegar Tree, 1951; UA070.001.021.00009 (Box 21)
  - The Animal Kingdom, 1952; UA070.001.021.00010 (Box 21)
  - An Inspector Calls, 1952; UA070.001.021.00011 (Box 21)
  - Mr. Whitcomb's Genie, 1952; UA070.001.021.00012 (Box 21)
  - Ten Nights in a Barroom, 1952; UA070.001.021.00013 (Box 21)
  - Anna Lucasta, 1953; UA070.001.021.00014 (Box 21)
  - Come Back Little Sheba, 1953; UA070.001.021.00015 (Box 21)
  - Season in the Sun, 1953; UA070.001.021.00016 (Box 21)
  - Summer and Smoke, 1953; UA070.001.021.00017 (Box 21)
  - Valiant, 1953; UA070.001.021.00018 (Box 21)
  - See How They Run, 1953; UA070.001.022.00001 (Box 22)
  - All My Sons, 1954; UA070.001.022.00002 (Box 22)
  - Death Takes a Holiday, 1954; UA070.001.022.00003 (Box 22)
  - The Rose Tattoo, 1954; UA070.001.022.00004 (Box 22)
  - Two Blind Mice, 1954; UA070.001.022.00005 (Box 22)
  - The Innocents, 1955; UA070.001.022.00006 (Box 22)
  - Love Rides the Rails, 1955; UA070.001.022.00007 (Box 22)
  - Picnic, 1955; UA070.001.022.00008 (Box 22)
  - Uncle Harry, 1955; UA070.001.022.00009 (Box 22)
  - The White Sheep of the Family, 1955; UA070.001.022.00010 (Box 22)
  - Blood Wedding, 1956; UA070.001.022.00011 (Box 22)
  - An Italian Straw Hat, 1956; UA070.001.022.00012 (Box 22)
  - King of Hearts, 1956; UA070.001.022.00013 (Box 22)
  - The Lady's Not for Burning, 1956; UA070.001.022.00014 (Box 22)
  - Antigone, 1957; UA070.001.023.00001 (Box 23)
  - Bus Stop, 1957; UA070.001.023.00002 (Box 23)
  - The Glass Menagerie, 1957; UA070.001.023.00003 (Box 23)
  - Hannah Garroway, 1958; UA070.001.023.00004 (Box 23)
  - Harvey, 1958; UA070.001.023.00005 (Box 23)
  - Separate Tables, 1958; UA070.001.023.00006 (Box 23)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, 1959; UA070.001.023.00007 (Box 23)
  - The Curious Savage, 1959; UA070.001.023.00008 (Box 23)
  - A View from the Bridge, 1959; UA070.001.023.00009 (Box 23)
  - The Acceptors, 1960; UA070.001.023.00010 (Box 23)
  - The Girls in 509, 1960; UA070.001.023.00011 (Box 23)
  - Look Back in Anger, 1960; UA070.001.023.00012 (Box 23)
  - The Autumn Garden, 1961; UA070.001.023.00013 (Box 23)
  - Come Back Little Sheba, 1961; UA070.001.023.00014 (Box 23)
  - The Madwoman of Chaillot, 1962; UA070.001.024.00001 (Box 24)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, 1962; UA070.001.024.00002 (Box 24)
  - Long Day's Journey into Night, 1963; UA070.001.024.00003 (Box 24)
  - Death of a Salesman, 1964; UA070.001.024.00004 (Box 24)
  - A Thurber Carnival, 1964; UA070.001.024.00005 (Box 24)
  - Magic Circle Theater, 1993; UA070.001.025.00001 (Box 25)
  - Cinderella Three, 1958; UA070.001.025.00002 (Box 25)
  - Johnny Appleseed, 1958; UA070.001.025.00003 (Box 25)
  - The Wizard of Oz, 1959 -- 1964; UA070.001.025.00004 (Box 25)
  - The Wonderful Tang, 1959; UA070.001.025.00005 (Box 25)
  - Productions, 1960; UA070.001.025.00006 (Box 25)
  - Seven League Boots, 1960; UA070.001.025.00007 (Box 25)
  - Beauty and the Beast, 1961; UA070.001.025.00008 (Box 25)
  - The Secret Garden, 1962; UA070.001.025.00009 (Box 25)
  - Snow White, 1962; UA070.001.025.00010 (Box 25)
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1963; UA070.001.025.00011 (Box 25)
  - Tom Sawyer, 1963; UA070.001.025.00012 (Box 25)
  - Cinderella, 1964; UA070.001.025.00013 (Box 25)
  - Puck and the Tinkers, 1964; UA070.001.025.00014 (Box 25)
  - Rip Van Winkle, 1964; UA070.001.025.00015 (Box 25)
  - The Old Wive's Tale, 1965; UA070.001.025.00016 (Box 25)
  - Once Upon A Mattress, 1965; UA070.001.025.00017 (Box 25)
  - Rhinoceros and the Leader, 1965; UA070.001.025.00018 (Box 25)
  - Many Moons, 1959; UA070.001.025.00019 (Box 25)
  - Toad of Toad Hall, 1965; UA070.001.025.00020 (Box 25)
  - Grand Duchess of Gerolstein, 1968; UA070.001.025.00021 (Box 25)
  - Prince and the Pauper, 1968; UA070.001.025.00022 (Box 25)
  - Peter Pan, 1971; UA070.001.025.00023 (Box 25)
  - Voyage to the Moon, 1972; UA070.001.025.00024 (Box 25)
  - "This Property is Condemned," n.d., UA070.001.026.00001 (Box 26)
  - Julie Portman, 1982; UA070.001.026.00002 (Box 26)
  - Big and Little, 1980; UA070.001.026.00003 (Box 26)
  - The Morning After Optimism, 1977; UA070.001.026.00004 (Box 26)
  - One-Act Plays (three), 1936; UA070.001.027.00001 (Box 27)
  - The Brat Sings, 1937; UA070.001.027.00002 (Box 27)
  - Conditional Surrender, 1937; UA070.001.027.00003 (Box 27)
  - The Imperial Monopoly, 1937; UA070.001.027.00004 (Box 27)
  - Obverse and Reverse, 1937; UA070.001.027.00005 (Box 27)
  - They Also Serve, 1937; UA070.001.027.00006 (Box 27)
  - Why Women Leave Home, 1937; UA070.001.027.00007 (Box 27)
  - Mr. Woodruff's Class, 1944; UA070.001.027.00008 (Box 27)
  - Gambit, 1948; UA070.001.027.00009 (Box 27)
  - The Wedding Morning, 1949; UA070.001.027.00010 (Box 27)
  - Harness, 1950; UA070.001.027.00011 (Box 27)
  - Pretzel Night, 1950; UA070.001.027.00012 (Box 27)
  - Another Way Out, 1951; UA070.001.027.00013 (Box 27)
  - Family Album, 1951; UA070.001.027.00014 (Box 27)
  - Andromache, 1952; UA070.001.027.00015 (Box 27)
  - One-Act Plays (two), 1951; UA070.001.027.00016 (Box 27)
  - Play production class programs, 1929 -- 1933; UA070.001.027.00017 (Box 27)
  - [No Title], n.d., UA070.001.028.00001 (Box 28)
  - Across These Lands, 1944; UA070.001.028.00002 (Box 28)
  - Are Your Hands Tied?, 1916; UA070.001.028.00003 (Box 28)
  - The Art of Being Bored, 1920; UA070.001.028.00004 (Box 28)
  - Carnival of the Animals, 1952; UA070.001.028.00005 (Box 28)
  - Christmas, 1942; UA070.001.028.00006 (Box 28)
  - Clear Conscience, UA070.001.028.00007 (Box 28)
  - The Elixir, UA070.001.028.00008 (Box 28)
  - Etienne Decroux, 1957; UA070.001.028.00009 (Box 28)
  - House Divided, 1960; UA070.001.028.00010 (Box 28)
  - Humble Pie, 1936 -- 1940; UA070.001.028.00011 (Box 28)
  - The Hunter, 1952; UA070.001.028.00012 (Box 28)
  - Joseph, n.d., UA070.001.028.00013 (Box 28)
  - A Matter of Principle, 1940; UA070.001.028.00014 (Box 28)
  - Mikko, Fox and the Dragon, n.d., UA070.001.028.00015 (Box 28)
  - The Molluse, 1942; UA070.001.028.00016 (Box 28)
  - Night in a Pillbox, 1938 -- 1942; UA070.001.028.00017 (Box 28)
  - Orestes, n.d., UA070.001.028.00018 (Box 28)